And here we are back in JupyterLab.
다시 유피터랩에 왔네요
It's been a minute.
1분 됐어요
We've been working in Colab for last week, and now we're back to to Jupyter and running locally, where
지난주에 콜랍에서 작업했고 다시 주피터로 가서 현지에서 조깅합니다
we will be enjoying ourselves today.
오늘 즐겁게 보낼 거예요
Uh, before we get to the code and looking at what we're going to do, let's remind ourselves the leaderboards,
코드로 가서 무엇을 할 것인지 살펴보기 전에 leaderboard를
which looked at coding abilities of frontier models just to see who is at the in the top of the pack
다시 한 번 짚어보죠. 개척 모델의 코딩 능력을 살펴보고 누가 코딩의 상위권에 있는지 보기
when it comes to coding.
위해서요.
So the vellum leaderboard you might remember from the AI company, vellum uh, has uh, the human eval
인공지능 회사인 피지 리더보드에 인체 평가가 있어요 간단한
uh, metric, which is the simple Python test.
파이썬 테스트죠
Um, and you can see against this metric that GPT four zero leads the way.
이 수치와 비교하면 GPT 40이 가장 앞섰어요
And then if we look down Claude three sonnet not doing so great down here.
클로드 3번 소네트가 아래를 내려다보면 잘 안 풀리네요
Um, now, for various reasons, I feel like this perhaps isn't the most up to date.
여러 가지 이유로 이게 최신 자료는 아닌 것 같네요
I notice elsewhere it doesn't have llama 3.1 on this site, so I'm thinking that perhaps this is a bit
다른 곳에는 라마 3이 없더라고요 이 사이트에는 1개 있어요 비트가 좀 오래된 것 같네요
I also know that human eval isn't the best of the tests, and I'm more interested in the seal leaderboard
인간 평가가 최고가 아니라는 것도 알아요 저는 코딩의 인장 순위표에 더 관심이
for coding.
있죠
And if you come into this and you read their blurb, you'll see that they do a number of different kinds
여기 와서 설명서를 읽어보면 다양한 코딩 테스트를 한다는 걸
of coding tests, including human eval, but also including live codebench, a bunch of programming
알 수 있어요 인간 평가도 있고 라이브 코드벤치도 있고 다수의 프로그래밍 퍼즐과 다른
puzzles, and a few others.
것들도 있어요
And so I feel like this is super comprehensive.
아주 포괄적인 것 같아요
I'm also pleased to see that llama 3.1 is on their list, and so I get the impression that this is also
라마 3도 반갑고요 1도 포함되어 있어요. 그래서 이건 최근의 get이라는
more recent.
느낌이 들어요.
And top of this leaderboard is Claude 3.5 sonnet, followed by GPT four zero, followed by Mistral large
순위표의 1위는 클로드 3이에요 5 소네트, 그다음은 GPT 40 미스트랄 라지
and open source model Mistral in third place.
오픈 소스 모델 미스트랄이 3위죠
So this gives us a sense of what's going on.
어떤 상황인지 알 수 있죠
Let's see if GPT four are many features.
GPT 4가 기능이 많은지 보죠
Not that I can see.
제가 보기엔 없어요
Uh, and that might suggest that we're going to need to use GPT four.
그렇다면 GPT 4를 사용해야 할 수도 있겠네요
Oh, if we're going to want to, uh, really compare the top models on this front.
톱모델들을 정면에서 비교하고 싶다면 이렇게 하세요
But you can feel free to use GPT two for mini, uh, if you'd rather be, uh, bit more frugal.
미니 비트는 GPT 2를 쓰세요 좀 더 검소하게 쓰고 싶다면요
Saved a bit of money.
비트 비트 좀 아꼈죠
Uh, regardless, let's go over to Jupyter Lab and let's go into week four and into day three to see
어쨌든 주피터 랩으로 가서 4주 차와 3일째 되는 날 이번 주 코드를 보죠
the code for this week, when we are going to be doing code generation and building an app around it.
코드 생성과 그걸 중심으로 앱을 만들 거예요
And as usual, this is a lot of things going on for what we'll be learning today.
오늘도 많은 걸 배울 거예요
One of them is actually about the problem of generating code.
그중 하나는 코드 생성 문제예요
Um, but we're also going to be using this as a way of exploring, comparing different models, um,
또한 이를 활용해 다양한 모델을 탐구하고 비교하고 기존의 순위표를 검토하며
looking at leaderboards as we just have, understanding how to solve a business problem with LM solutions.
LM 솔루션으로 비즈니스 문제를 해결하는 방법도 이해하려고 해요
And you know what you might notice here?
여기서 뭐가 보이는지 아세요?
There's there's this little thing here, we're going to get another opportunity to play with Gradio
여기 작은 게 있는데요 Gadio와 함께 플레이할 기회가
and to show what it's like to package things up into a prototype, because that is just such a great
또 있을 겁니다 프로토타입으로 패키지하는 게 어떤 건지 보여드릴 겁니다
way to collaborate with others on your LM solutions.
LM 솔루션에 관해 다른 이들과 협업할 수 있는 아주 좋은 방법이거든요
So we're going to embark on this by running some imports, and we're then going to set our environment
임포트 실행으로 착수하겠습니다 그런 다음 환경 변수를 설정하죠 일반적인 LoadInFv를
variables using the usual load env.
이용해서요
And it's a nice time for me to remind you once again to have a EMV file.
EMV 파일을 준비하라고 다시 한 번 말씀드리죠
This time we'll be using OpenAI and anthropic.
이번에는 오픈라이와 인어로픽을 사용할 거예요
So have that set up, uh, in this, uh, cell here, we initialize the OpenAI and the cloud interfaces
여기 이 셀에서 오픈AI와 클라우드 인터페이스를 평소처럼 초기화합니다 오픈AI와 클라우드
as usual, and we'll use OpenAI and cloud 3.5.
3을 사용하죠 5분
Sorry.
미안해요
We'll use GPT four and cloud 3.5.
GPT4와 클라우드 3을 사용하죠 5분
Sonnet uh, which were in the top two positions in that leaderboard.
순위표에서 상위 2위에 드는 소네트였죠
So now we have, uh, it's time to develop our system message and our user prompt.
이제 시스템 메시지와 사용자 프롬프트를 개발할 차례죠
And I'm using the same approach that we used back in the day.
예전에 썼던 방법을 그대로 쓰고 있어요
It feels like an age ago now where system message we just hard code it.
시스템 메시지에 하드 코드를 넣는 건 옛날 일 같아요
And the user prompt we have something where we pass in a variable and generate the user prompt for that
사용자 프롬프트에는 변수에서 전달하는 무언가가 있고 그 변수를 위한 사용자 프롬프트를
variable.
생성하죠
So the system message I've gone with is you're an assistant that re-implements Python code in high performance
제가 전달한 시스템 메시지는 당신은 고성능 C+4, M1 Mac으로 파이썬 코드를 재구성하는
C plus plus four and M1 Mac.
조수라는 거예요
Obviously I'm using an M1 Mac right here.
제가 쓰는 건 M1맥이에요
Um, and I suggest that you substitute in here whatever kind of environment you have to make this most
여러분께 가장 적절한 환경을 갖추기 위해 어떤 것이든 여기서 대체하는 걸 권해드립니다
appropriate for you and you may need to do some some tweaking, particularly with the C plus plus setup
약간의 수정이 필요할 수도 있어요 특히 C 플러스 셋업에서요 이게 제대로 되도록
to make sure that this works for you.
하기 위해서요
Respond only with C plus plus code.
C 플러스 플러스 코드만 사용하세요
Use comments sparingly.
댓글은 아껴 써요
Do not provide any explanation other than occasional comments.
가끔 댓글 다는 것 외에는 어떤 설명도 하지 마세요
The C plus plus response needs to produce an identical output in the fastest possible time, so this
C++ 응답은 가장 빠른 시간 내에 동일한 출력을 내야 합니다 조금
is a little bit more wordy than the prompt I showed you in the slide a second ago, but this is what
전에 보여드린 프롬프트보다 좀 더 단어 같죠 하지만 약간 수정하면 가장
I found worked best with some tweaking around, and you'll see that the user prompt is even more wordy.
잘 되는 걸 찾았어요 사용자 프롬프트는 더 단어 같죠
Rewrite this Python code to C plus plus fastest possible implementation.
파이썬 코드를 C+로 다시 쓰고 가장 빠른 구현을 더하세요
It's a bit repetitive.
비트가 좀 반복적이에요
Um, and then just here you can see I've cheated a little bit from doing some of my experiments.
그리고 여기 보시면 실험에서 약간 비트를 썼어요
I found actually, as you'll discover, uh, maybe this is as suggested by the leaderboards.
알게 되겠지만 순위표에 나온 대로일 수도 있어요
Claude didn't need this extra hinting, but GPT four did need this.
클로드는 이런 힌트가 필요 없었지만 GPT 4에는 이게 필요했죠
Otherwise, the C plus plus code it generated didn't work.
그렇지 않으면, 생성된 C++ 코드가 작동하지 않아요
Um, I had to say pay attention to number types to ensure that there are no overflows.
넘치지 않도록 숫자 유형을 잘 봐야 해요
And remember to Hash include all necessary cplusplus patches such as or packages such as.
해시는 필수적인 모든 패치를 포함하는 걸 기억하세요 패키지 같은 거요
I even had to actually explicitly name a particular package, which if I didn't, uh, GPT four would
특정 패키지에 명시적으로 이름을 붙여야만 했어요 그렇게 하지 않으면 GPT 4가 Cplusplus
generate the cplusplus code, but not correctly include that package.
코드를 생성할 테니까요 하지만 정확히 해당 패키지를 포함하진 않죠
So for whatever reason, that's something that I ended up having to do.
이유는 모르겠지만 결국 그렇게 해야만 했어요
Uh, maybe when you try this out, you'll find that doesn't happen.
이걸 써보면 그렇지 않다는 걸 알게 될 거예요
You'll find a better way to prompt it without needing to be quite so directive.
그렇게 명령조로 말하지 않고도 더 잘 전달할 방법을 찾을 거예요
Uh, it feels a little bit like that's cheating for GPT four, and we should disqualify it.
4번 비트를 조작하는 것 같아서 실격시켜야 할 것 같아요
But there we go.
하지만 됐어요
Anyway, with that in mind, we now, uh, run this function to we've now defined a function to create
어쨌든 그걸 염두에 두고 이제 이 함수를 실행 이 사용자 프롬프트를 생성할 함수를
this user prompt.
정의했죠
And then this section here will be very familiar to you.
이 부분은 아주 익숙할 거예요
Uh, messages for uh is where we create the list.
음 메시지 목록은 여기서 만들어요
We know so well now, uh, with two elements, uh, the role system for the system message and role
지금은 두 가지 요소로 잘 알려져 있죠 시스템 메시지를 위한 역할 시스템과 사용자 프롬프트를
user for the user prompt.
위한 역할 사용자요
Um, so that generates that messages list given Python, uh, and now Little utility function called
파이썬 을 이용해서 메시지 리스트를 생성하고 쓰기출력이라는 유틸리티 함수가
writeoutput.
있어요
That will take some cplusplus code, and it will just strip out anything in there that, uh, shouldn't
그러려면 문장 코드가 필요해요 거기 있어선 안 될 건 뭐든 제거해 줄 거예요
be there.
모델은 그에 반응하는 경향이 있어요 이건 위에 두고 이건 아래에 두는 거죠
And so I just replace that with, I just remove that from the, from the text and then save it to a
그래서 그걸 텍스트에서 제거한 다음 최적화된 .cpp이라는 cplusplus
cplusplus file called optimized dot cpp.
파일에 저장했어요
So when this runs we will see a file appearing in our directory optimized cpp.
이게 실행되면 파일이 디렉터리 최적화된 cpp에 나타나는 걸 보게 되죠
And when it's called.
언제 부르는지도 알고요
All right.
좋아요
And then here is uh function optimized GPT that is going to call the GPT API.
그리고 여기 함수 최적화된 GPT가 있습니다 GPT API를 호출할 거예요
We're going to call OpenAI dot chat dot completions dot create.
OpenAI.Tat.완료.Create라고 입력할게요
Why do you know that that call by now, uh, model equals OpenAI model messages is and now we pass in
모델과 OpenAI 모델 메시지가 같다는 것을 어떻게 아셨나요? 파이썬 을 위한 메시지를
the messages for Python and we set that to be streaming.
전달하는 것을 스트리밍으로 설정했죠
And we do for chunk in stream.
덩어리 인 스트림도 있어요
That means that the results come back and we print each little chunk as it comes back.
즉, 결과가 나오면 그 결과에 따라 조금씩 프린트하는 거죠
And then at the end we write this to a file.
그리고 마지막에 이걸 파일로 작성해요
Hopefully I don't need to go through this because this is super familiar to you.
이런 건 안 해도 되겠죠? 당신한텐 익숙하잖아요
Now you've seen this a hundred times and side by side with it, here is the equivalent version for Claude
이걸 100번은 보셨을 겁니다 이것과 나란히서요 이건 클로드가 같은 걸 하는
doing the same thing.
동일한 버전이죠
We're going to call Claude.
클로드한테 전화할게요
Messages dot stream for the Claude model.
메시지 클로드 모델에게 점 흐름 보내주세요
Uh, we you remember in Claude's case, we have to provide the system message separately to the user
클로드의 경우를 기억하시겠지만 사용자 프롬프트에는 시스템 메시지를 따로 제공해야
prompt.
해요
So there we go.
자, 됐어요
This is, again, a construct you're very familiar with.
이것 역시 여러분이 아주 익숙한 구조죠
We have to tell it the maximum number of tokens.
패의 최대 개수를 알려 줘야 해요
And then this is how we do the streaming back.
이렇게 스트리밍을 하는 거예요
Same kind of thing.
비슷한 거예요
Printing writing the output.
인쇄해서 출력하는 거죠
All right.
좋아요
At this point, because we're getting ready to try this out for reals I will execute these two.
이 시점에서, 실제로 해볼 준비가 되어 있기 때문에 이 두 가지를 실행할게요
And then I'm going to to pause for the next video.
그런 다음 다음 다음 비디오로 일시 정지하죠
And in the next video you see us, you'll see us giving this a try and seeing how GPT four and Claude
다음 영상에서는 저희가 이 작업을 시도하고 GPT 4와 클로드 3이 어떻게 작동하는지
3.5 sonnet perform when faced with this challenge.
보여 드릴게요 이 난관에 직면했을 때 5개의 소네트가 공연되죠
See you then.
그때 봐요